houstonpublicmedia.org 2019-12-16

# UHS Privacy Notice - University of Houston System

### **Privacy Notice**

**  
Scope of Privacy Notice**

This Privacy Notice applies to information that we collect when you visit the websites in the domains of the University of Houston System ([www.uhsystem.edu](http://www.uhsystem.edu/)), University of Houston ([www.uh.edu](http://www.uh.edu/)),  University of Houston – Clear Lake ([www.uhcl.edu](http://www.uhcl.edu/)), University of Houston – Downtown ([www.uhd.edu](http://www.uhd.edu/)), and University of Houston – Victoria ([www.uhv.edu](http://www.uhv.edu/)) (collectively and individually referred to as **“University** ,” “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”) and other websites that we own or control and link or refer to this Privacy Notice (together, the **“Sites”** ), as well as to the information that we collect from you when you provide us information through the mail, over the phone, or other method outside of the Sites, mobile applications and services.

Unless otherwise indicated on a specific Site, the University is the data controller for all information collected under this Notice.  Contact information for the University’s Privacy Officer is listed at the end of this Notice.

**Personal Information We Collect and Process:**

When you access or use the Sites or interact with us, we may collect and process the following types of information about you:

**“Personal Information”** is any information that we can reasonably use to identify you. If you are located in the European Economic Area **(“EEA”)** , Personal Information includes all Personal Data as defined under EEA laws.

**“Sensitive Personal Information”** includes special categories of Personal Information (e.g., racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health, and data concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation) for which applicable law provides enhanced protections.

The table below describes in most cases the Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information that we collect, why we collect it, and our legal basis for processing it.

**Purposes of Processing** | **Categories of Personal Information** | **Legal Basis**  
As part of the undergraduate and graduate admissions process, we collect applicant Personal Information to evaluate applications. We also may obtain Personal Information from third parties, such as other schools, references, family members, and education partners (e.g., The Common Application, Inc., Law School Admissions Council, The College Board, etc.) as part of an application package. | Name, address, contact details, race/ethnicity, demographic information, educational history, reference, photographs, letters, PeopleSoft ID, and other relevant information as part of the application package. | 

_Legitimate Interest:_ Personal Information collected through the graduate or undergraduate application is necessary to evaluate candidates for admissions and for our internal statistical and analytics purposes

_Consent:_ Processing of Sensitive Personal Information for purposes stated above

_Contract:_   If a contract is involved, processing will be handled for purposes stated above

_Legal Requirement:   _Personal Information and Sensitive Information are processed and maintained as required by law  
To  process financial aid and scholarship applications and awards | Name, address, contact details, demographic information, salary history, PeopleSoft ID, tax forms and other relevant information to evaluate financial aid/scholarship eligibility and opportunities. | 

_Legitimate Interest:_

Personal Information collected through the financial aid application is necessary to evaluate whether the applicant is eligible to receive financial aid/scholarships

_Consent:_ Processing of Sensitive Personal Information for purposes stated above

_Contract:_ to process Personal Information and Sensitive Information pursuant to contract

_Legal Requirement:   _Personal Information and Sensitive Information are processed and maintained as required by law  
To support course registration and academic matters, such as coursework, test results, grading; to investigate claims of academic misconduct | Name, Campus AD ID, PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, contact information | 

_Legitimate Interest:_

Personal Information collected for matriculated students, staff, faculty and members of the public, as appropriate for the course, to enroll in courses or classes, and administer academic matters  
To process requests for housing and dining services | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, contact information, dietary restrictions, special interests | 

_Legitimate Interest:_

Personal Information collected to facilitate housing requests and for available meal plans

_Consent:_  Processing of Sensitive Information for purposes stated above

_Contract:   _Processing Personal Information pursuant to contract  
To provide online training and distance educational programs | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, contact information, demographic information | 

_Legitimate Interest:_

To facilitate provision of education courses to matriculated students, staff, faculty and members of the public, as appropriate for the course  
  
For research purposes, to recruit, screen, and enroll individuals as research subjects, conduct clinical studies, and/or process data or biological samples from individuals | Name, contact/demographic information, other personal data as necessary for the research protocol, such as health information, data and/or biological samples | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To  conduct human subjects  research

_Consent:_ Written consent requirements approved by University IRB for specific research projects

_Contract:   _To examine, evaluate, and analyze in compliance with research contracts and awards  
To establish and conduct collaborations with external scientists or companies for research purposes | Name, contact information, demographics and credentials of scientist collaborating with the University | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To establish and collaborate on research and enter into intellectual property (IP)/licensing agreements

_Contract:_ Establishment of research contracts/awards and IP agreements  
To recruit students for athletics teams, provide athletic scholarships,  administer athletics programs | Name, Campus ID, PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, demographic information, health information, sport statistics | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To recruit and coach student athletes, provide academic support services, provide and administer athletic scholarships, provide dietary and nutritional education, health care, training and sports medicine services

_Consent:   _Upon written consent from the individual, for the purposes stated above

_Contract_ :  To provide athletic scholarships and administer athletics programs as required by contract  
To provide student outreach and support services, including but not limited to reasonable accommodations, health services, tutoring, counseling and other assistance as needed | Name, Campus ID, PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, demographic information, health information; other sensitive information | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To facilitate student academic achievement; provide health services, tutoring, counseling and other assistance as needed

_Consent:   _Upon written consent from the individual, Sensitive Information will be processed for the purposes stated above

_Legal Requirement:   _Sensitive Information will processed to provide reasonable accommodations  
To process employment applications | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, demographic information, resumes | _Legitimate Interest:_ For individuals interested in employment opportunities, processing applications  
To enroll in wellness programs | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, health information | 

_Legitimate Interest:_ For eligible individuals interested in participating in a variety of wellness programs, courses, activities, facilitate enrollment and communications about the programs

_Contract:_ If there is a contract for participation in wellness programs, Personal Information is processed pursuant to that contract  
To administer employment activities of University faculty, staff and student workers | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, contact information, demographic information, dependent information, financial information, employment records, photographs, health information | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To comply with legal requirements, administer payroll and benefits, provide reasonable accommodations, administer FMLA and sick leave policies, improve hiring practices, for regulatory reporting and auditing and other University processes and functions

_Consent:_   Sensitive information will be processed for the purposes provided above

_Legal Requirement:   _Sensitive Information will be processed to provide reasonable accommodations and to administer FMLA and sick leave policies  
To process visa applications for incoming student, staff and faculty from overseas | Name, demographic information, financial information, passport number | _Legal Requirement_  
For marketing purposes and donations, and to process requests for brochures and other information | Name, contact information, financial information, payment information | _Legitimate Interest:_ To collect and process donations/gifts and donor information, to send brochures or other requested information  
To process payments such as tuition and other student fees, parking passes and permits, event registrations and tickets to events | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID (if applicable), contact information, payment information | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To receive and process payments for tuition, fees, parking, and to register and receive payments for sports, cultural, educational and other University

events

_Contract:_  To process registration and payment for the purposes stated above  
To submit requests for services (e.g., IT technical help, chat line, etc.) | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, contact information | 

_Legitimate Interest:_ To process service requests from students, staff and faculty

_Contract:_ If there is a contract that governs your use of such services, Personal Information is processed pursuant to that contract  
Website account registration | Name, contact information, alumni status | _Legitimate Interest:_ For websites that require registration for access, to facilitate the registration  
Travel administration | Name, Campus AD ID,  PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, contact information, passport number, loyalty membership information, emergency contacts | 

_Legitimate Interest:_ To facilitate travel arrangements and coordination for students and affiliated travelers through University programs

_Contract:_ If there is a contract that governs your use of travel sites, Personal Information is processed pursuant to that contract  
To investigate claims of discrimination/harassment | Name, contact information, PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, other personal data if applicable -- age, demographic information, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, health data, sexual orientation, and salary and other employment history | 

_Legitimate interest:   _To investigate claims and complaints of discrimination/harassment

_Consent:   _Claimant information will be processed for the purposes stated above

_Legal Requirement_  
For safety, risk management purposes | Name, address, contact information, PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, age, health information, and other information as necessary to achieve purposes. | 

_Legitimate Interest:   _To provide a safe, secure campus, provide occupational and environmental safety, to investigate suspected criminal activity, to evaluate workers compensation and injury claims

_Legal Requirement_  
To receive, investigate, and resolve claims of misconduct and/or violation of University policies; to conduct disciplinary proceedings | Name, address, contact information, PeopleSoft ID and/or Banner ID, age, health information, and other information as necessary to achieve purposes. | 

_Legitimate interest:   _To investigate claims and complaints of misconduct and violation of University policies

_Consent:   _Claimant information will be processed for the purposes stated above  
To provide access to the official University app | Campus AD ID, location | 

_Legitimate Interest:_ To provide access to information available through the University mobile application.  To provide notifications through the University mobile application

_Consent:_ Upon written consent from the individual to use the mobile app  
  
A cookie is a file designed to contain a small amount of user and website information stored on a user’s computer. The file interacts with the user and the website to provide a webpage tailored to the user through its awareness of information held within the file.

Cookies also have the ability to carry all or parts of the information stored within the file to other websites that the user may visit or to third parties.

This Cookie Policy applies to the cookies we use when you visit any of the University websites and any other websites that we own or control and link or refer to this Cookie Policy (together, the “ **Sites** ”).

This cookie policy provides you with more information about cookies, what types of cookies we use and how we use them. Our Sites use cookies with the intention of providing you with a user experience that best suits your needs, while concurrently allowing us to improve the design and functionality of our Sites. Cookies can be adjusted or disabled, and this policy provides you with instructions to do so.

A third-party cookie is placed by a domain other than that of the website the user is visiting.

A session cookie is temporary, linking the actions of a user during the any given browser session. When the browser is closed, the cookie is deleted.

A permanent cookie, also known as a persistent cookie, is stored for a specific period of time and activates each time the user visits the website that created the cookie.

We use third-party, session and persistent cookies and similar technology to collect aggregate (non-personal) information about Sites usage by all of our visitors and to help us remember you and your preferences when you revisit the Sites. These cookies may stay on your browser into the future until they expire or you delete them. We also use technology to remember you the next time you log in. Some of these cookies are erased when you close your browser window and some persist for a period of time. Further general information about cookies and how they work is available at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

We may allow selected third parties to place cookies through the Sites to provide us with better insights into the use of the Sites or user demographics or to provide relevant advertising to you. These third parties may collect information about a user’s online activities over time and across different websites when he or she uses our Sites.

The cookies used on our Sites may include, but are not limited to, the following:

Category | Description  
  
Session

| 

These cookies expire when the browser is closed. The purpose of these cookies is to temporarily retain information related to the user’s visit to a Site, such as the number of visits, average time spent on the Site, and what pages have been loaded.  
  
Permanent

| 

These cookies remain in operation, even when the browser is closed. The purpose of these cookies is to retain information to help the user avoid retyping data.  
  
Third-party

| 

Third parties install these cookies to collect certain information for statistical purposes and conducting research into behavior, demographics, and similar topics about our users.  
  
Analytics

| 

These cookies help us understand how our visitors engage with our Sites. These cookies collect information and report website usage statistics. Some of these cookies are used to see how people use our Sites, which helps us improve it.  
  
Preferences

| 

These cookies allow our Sites to remember information that changes the way the site behaves or looks for you, such as your preferred language or the region you are in. For instance, by remembering your region, a website may be able to provide you with local weather reports or traffic news. These cookies can also assist you in changing text size, font, and other parts of web pages that you can personalize. Loss of the information stored in a preference cookie may make the website experience less functional but should not prevent it from working.  
  
Security

| 

We use security cookies to authenticate users, prevent fraudulent use of login credentials, and protect user data from unauthorized parties.

Some of these cookies may collect the request made by your browser to the server hosting the website which includes the IP address, the date and time of connection and the page you ask for. We use this information to ensure the security of our Sites.

Some of these cookies help make the Sites work and deliver services that the website visitor expects, like navigating around web pages or accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies, the Sites cannot function properly.  
  
Advertising | We use cookies to make advertising more engaging to users and more valuable to publishers and advertisers. Some common applications of these cookies are to select advertising based on what’s relevant to a user; to improve reporting on campaign performance; and, to avoid showing ads the user has already seen.  
  
You can change your cookie settings by reviewing your internet browser’s cookie options. The links below to popular browsers may help you understand your cookie options better. Typically, such information can be found under the browser’s ‘Help’, ‘Preferences’ or ‘Options’ menus.  Information about how you can opt out of Google's use of cookies can be obtained by visiting Google's [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) and how you can opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Some of our Sites engage in online interest-based advertising to enhance your experience and show you advertisements that might interest you. Like many organizations, we and our advertising partners display tailored interest-based advertising using information you make available to us when you interact with our Sites.  Interest-based ads, also sometimes referred to as personalized or targeted ads, are displayed to you based on information from activities such as searching on our Sites or visiting websites that contain our content or ads. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers.

To learn more about interest-based ads or to opt-out of receiving third-party interest based ads, please visit [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/) or [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note that if you opt out of interest-based advertising, you will still see advertisements – they will just not be tailored to your interests.  Also note that deleting browser cookies can remove the cookie preferences you have made, so you may need to opt-out again in the future.

Should you choose to decline or block cookies by adjusting your browser settings, including cookies essential to the Sites.  Please note that all or parts of our Sites may not be functional or accessible to you. Our Sites will issue cookies as soon you visit the Sites, unless your browser cookie settings are adjusted to prevent such an occurrence. Please review the information provided in this cookie policy on adjusting cookie settings for the browser of your choice.

If you live or provide us information from outside the United States, data protection laws in the United States may differ from those in your home country.  Therefore, if you are a user from outside of the United States, by providing us with your Personal information, you acknowledge that your information will be transferred to the United States, processed on servers in the United States, and handled in accordance with the applicable data protection laws, including the GDPR if you are located within the EEA.  In certain instances, your Personal Information may be transferred to other countries, including your home country.  Regardless, we will take all reasonable steps to protect your privacy in accordance with applicable law and University policy. **Information Security**

Personal Information you submit, such as your name, address and other contact information, may be collected by us for internal marketing and development purposes as well as to respond to your inquiry, complete a transaction for you, or fulfill other forms of customer service. You can choose not to receive marketing from us by “unsubscribing” using the instructions in any marketing email you receive from us or contacting the sender and requesting to be removed from further marketing emails.

If you are an individual located in the EEA only, you will have the following rights with regard to your Personal Data:

University students can manage privacy settings for their directory information in myUH Self Services or Banner. Faculty, staff and other University affiliates can manage their privacy settings in [P.A.S.S.](https://stanfordyou.stanford.edu/) (Employee Self Service).

You can choose not to receive emails from us by “unsubscribing” using the instructions in any email you receive from us.  This will not stop us from sending emails about your account or your transactions with us.

We keep your Personal Information for as long as needed to fulfill the particular purpose for which it was collected. We may also retain your records if legally required or to fulfill a legitimate interest.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Notice at any time. Prior to changes to the Privacy Notice, we will provide you notice, which shall be available at [privacyofficer@uh.edu](mailto:privacyofficer@uh.edu), prior to the effective date of any notice. Your provision of Personal Information to use after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

For more information on how we collect and process your Personal Information, or if you have any complaints please contact [privacyofficer@uh.edu](mailto:privacyofficer@uh.edu).

The effective date of this policy is May 25, 2018.
